【The fate that cannot be liberated】
【无法解脱的命运】
[Episode 10]
[第10集]
be patient.
要有耐心。
When I won first prize in equestrian
当我获得马术一等奖时
And got the most precious nine-segmented beetle in the snow mountain,
并得到雪山上最珍贵的九节虫甲虫，
I'll come back and feed you.
我会回来喂你的。
Make me proud.
让我自豪。
The rain in Nanjiang falls whenever it wants.
南江的雨 想下就下。
By the way, I heard that Ling was stopped on the street again.
对了，听说凌 又在街上被拦住了。
Yes, everyone is saying it now
是的，现在大家都在说
The He family has a daughter who is sought after by every household.
何家有一个 千家万户都追捧的女儿。
Father, since Ling has no lover,
父亲，既然凌没有情人，
She can be alone,
她可以独自一人，
As long as she is happy.
只要她快乐。
Yes, as long as she is happy.
是的，只要她幸福就好。
I think this will be
我想这将会是
It will be four years next month.
下个月就整整四年了。
Now Nanjiang is peaceful
如今南江太平
The people are safe and sound.
人民安然无恙。
I don’t know if our family has been freed from the disaster.
不知道我们一家人 是否已经从灾难中解脱出来了。
Father, during the years of suppressing bandits,
父亲，在剿匪的这些年里，
We have suffered countless injuries.
我们遭受了无数的伤害。
Last year when you led Qingxing and Jiuling to suppress the bandits,
去年你带着清星和九灵 剿匪的时候，
If it weren’t for Yang Ying, I’m afraid
如果不是杨颖，恐怕
You and Qingxing have long since frozen to death by the Canglan River.
你和庆星早就 冻死在沧澜河边了。
Last month, the emperor died,
上个月，皇帝去世了，
But we didn't make it back to the capital in time.
但我们没能 及时回到首都。
The emperor's decree has arrived, congratulations to the general.
皇帝的圣旨已到，贺将军。
Qingxing, take a look.
Qingxing, take a look.
Take a look.
看一看。
hurry up.
赶快。
Father…
父亲…
Everyone should take a good look.
大家都应该好好看看。
Father.
父亲。
Did you know that I won first place in the horseback archery competition?
你们知道我 在骑马射箭比赛中获得了第一名吗？
If not you, who else?
如果不是你，还能是谁？
I have never doubted this fact
我从未怀疑过这个事实
No one can surpass you.
没有人能超越你。
Ling,
凌,
There is another important thing in our family.
我们家还有另一件重要的事情。
Father, does the Emperor really want us to return to Beijing?
父亲，皇上真的 要我们回京吗？
And reward the He family with a title?
并奖励何家爵位？
Am I dreaming?
我不是在做梦吧？
This is real.
这是真的。
The emperor has always had a close relationship with Jiuling.
皇上一向与九灵关系密切，
He even gave it to you accidentally
他甚至不经意地给了你
His dragon pendant.
他的龙吊坠。
Is it possible that he is thinking of you?
难不成他在想你吗？
Freeze said.
别乱说。
Don't try to guess what the emperor is thinking.
不要试图猜测皇帝的想法。
The late emperor had just passed away;
已故皇帝刚刚去世，
His Highness ascended the throne when he was 15 years old.
殿下15岁时即位。
As his ministers, we should be loyal and responsible
作为他的大臣，我们应该 忠诚尽责
Help him become emperor with peace of mind.
帮助他安心当皇帝。
but if we go back
但如果我们回去
Will the Rong family's affairs reach a deadlock again?
荣家的事又会 陷入僵局吗？
Mr. Rong said nothing
荣爷什么也没说
Or contact us during these years.
或在这些年中联系我们。
I'm afraid he has given up on the idea.
恐怕他已经 放弃这个念头了。
Even if he mentions it again, we can still say that Ling has an imperial edict
就算他再提， 我们也可以说凌有圣旨
Return to Nanjiang
返回南江
And say no politely.
并委婉地说不。
As long as Mr. Rong can't wait
只要容大人等不及
And arranged a marriage for his son in the capital,
并在京城为儿子安排了婚事，
The deadlock will be resolved.
僵局将会得到解决。
However, I heard from the capital
然而，我从首都听说
Master Rong can only speak
容大师只能说话
A few characters can now be recognized.
现在可以认出几个字符了。
I'm afraid no one would want to marry him in this situation.
这种情况恐怕没人愿意嫁给他。
I'm tired. I'm going back to bed.
我累了。我要回去睡觉了。
【He is a mansion】
【他是豪宅】
Brother, my antidote failed.
师兄，我的解药没有成功。
I've tried countless times over the past four years
四年来我尝试过无数次
But no progress was made.
但没有任何进展。
I'm going back to Jialin soon.
我马上要回嘉林了。
Please help me.
请帮我。
【Prince Yong's Mansion】
【雍亲王府】
What are you doing? how dare you?
你在干什么？你怎么敢？
Are you going to put me under house arrest?
你要软禁我吗？
Is this the emperor's decision?
这是皇帝的决定吗？
Or is it the order of my royal brother?
还是我皇族兄弟的命令？
It doesn't matter whose decision it is.
谁的决定并不重要。
What matters is whether you obey orders.
重要的是你是否服从命令。
The emperor has been feeling unwell recently.
皇上最近身体不适，
Things can get messy.
事情可能会变得混乱。
Prince Yong, you should be obedient.
雍亲王，你还是乖乖听话吧
If you want to live.
如果你想活下去。
Stay in your mansion.
留在自己的豪宅里。
Where is Jiuling?
九岭在哪里？
Qiuting, go and have a look.
秋婷，你去看看吧。
OK
好的。
-Jiu Ling. - I am fine. Hongzao’s leg was injured.
-九龄。 - 我很好。红枣的腿受伤了。
it's all my fault. I shouldn't go hunting hares.
都是我的错。我不应该 去打野兔。
I hurt Jujube.
我让红枣受伤了。
Fortunately, her bones are fine.
幸运的是，她的骨头还好。
However, it seems
然而，似乎
Red algae cannot travel with us.
红藻不能和我们一起旅行。
In this case, you go first.
在这种情况下，你先走。
I walked behind with red dates
我带着红枣走在后面
Until I treated her in the next town.
直到我在下一个城镇给她治疗。
I'll take her there. The red algae is very close to me.
我会带她去。红藻离我很近。
How about I go with you?
我和你一起去怎么样？
I'm tired from riding, so I'll take a walk with you.
我骑累了，所以我会和你一起散步。
I'll stay too.
我也会留下来。
are you coming?
你来吗？
Second brother, will you join us?
二哥，你也加入我们吧？
Qiuting, take good care of them.
秋婷，好好照顾他们。
Take good care of Ling and your second sister-in-law.
好好照顾玲 和你二嫂。
【Wu's Steamed Bun Shop】
【吴氏包子店】
how?
如何？
Isn't it great?
不是很好吗？
The calligraphy is impeccable.
书法无可挑剔。
Auntie, look at this.
阿姨，你看这个。
Have a look at this too.
也看一下这个。
Let me see, let me see.
让我看看，让我看看。
Such quality fabric.
如此优质的面料。
excuse me.
打扰一下。
How many do you want?
你想要几个？
- here you go. - Thanks.
- 干得好。 - 谢谢。
How much do you need?
你需要多少？
OK
好的。
Just a moment please.
请稍等片刻。
So be it.
就这样吧。
Can you tell me where He Jiuling is?
你能告诉我贺九菱在哪里吗？
What did you say?
你说什么？
I'm looking for He Jiuling.
我在找何九菱。
Have you ever seen…
你有没有见过…
Looking for someone?
找人吧？
You should go to a government office.
你应该去政府办公室。
What are government agencies?
政府机关是什么？
- Come in, please. - Okay.
- 请进来 - 好的
[Yanchun House]
[Yanchun House]
Master, where are you going?
少爷，你要去哪里？
How about taking a break at our place?
到我们这里休息一下怎么样？
I need to go to a government office.
我需要去政府办公室。
Government agencies?
政府机关？
This is a government office.
这是政府办公室。
Master, you are my high official.
少爷，你是我的大官。
Can you help me find someone?
你能帮我找一个人吗？
Master, who are you looking for?
少爷你找谁？
Cuiliu, Yingge, come here.
Cuiliu, Yingge, come here.
future.
未来。
Master, who are you looking for?
少爷你找谁？
I'm looking for He Jiuling.
我在找何九菱。
He Jiuling?
He Jiuling?
Yes, we have her.
是的，我们有她。
Master, please come in, please come in.
少爷请进，请进。
hurry up.
快点，快点。
let's go.
我们走吧。
Come on, that's it.
来吧，就是这样。
right here.
就在这里。
Master, your cloak is so beautiful.
少爷，你的斗篷真漂亮。
Take it off and let me see. hurry up.
把它取下来让我看看。快点。
Where...where is He Jiuling?
哪里……何九菱在哪里？
He Jiuling? I am He Jiuling.
He Jiuling? I am He Jiuling.
Not just He Jiuling,
不只是何九菱，
even Zhang Jiuling, or Li Jiuling,
even Zhang Jiuling, or Li Jiuling,
We have them all here.
我们这里都有。
Come on, Master.
来吧，少爷。
You can call me whatever you want.
你可以随意称呼我。
Come on, let me undress you.
来吧，我给你脱衣服。
- Yes, yes, indeed. - Correct, absolutely correct.
- 是的，是的，确实如此。 - 正确，完全正确。
- you are lying. - Help him.
- 你在撒谎。 - 帮助他。
- fraud. - Don't be shy, Master.
- 骗子。 - 别害羞，少爷。
fraud. I need to find someone.
骗子。我需要去找人。
Master, don't leave.
少爷，你别走。
Don't go, Master.
别走，少爷。
Master, wait.
少爷，等等。
Don't go, Master. Master.
别走，少爷。少爷。
Slow down, Master.
慢点吧，少爷。
Master, don't run.
少爷，别跑。
Master, Master.
少爷，少爷。
Master.
少爷。
Master, don't go up. Master.
少爷，你别上去。少爷。
Master, you can't go up.
少爷，你不能上去。
Rooftops are very dangerous.
屋顶非常危险。
- let me see. - Take a look.
- 让我看看。 - 看一看。
It is not good?
这不是很好吗？
Very good indeed.
确实很好。
You should buy one too.
你也应该买一个。
Of course, that would be beautiful.
当然，那会很漂亮。
All right.
好吧。
There is no Dr. Ma.
没有马医生。
We should go to the drugstore first and buy some medicine to apply.
我们应该先去药店 买点药来涂。
I guess.
我猜。
He Jiuling. He Jiuling.
He Jiuling. He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
do not move. Stay there.
别动。呆在那里。
Stay here.
留在这。
Jiuling.
Jiuling.
♫Our life is very fulfilling♫
♫我们的生活很充实♫
♫ With joy and sadness ♫
♫ 带着喜悦和悲伤 ♫
♫ Desire for crystallization♫
♫ 渴望结晶 ♫
♫ Enter the bright galaxy ♫
♫ 进入明亮的星系 ♫
♫You turned around quietly♫
♫你静静地转过身♫
♫ Closed the marriage contract ♫
♫ 合上了婚书♫
♫Ask how many stars there are in the sky♫
♫问天上有多少颗星星♫
♫Write down what I miss you♫
♫写下对你的思念♫
How is this going?
这是怎么回事？
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫There is no escape from fate♫
♫命运无路可逃♫
♫Looking back, I see you waiting♫
♫回首，我看到你在等待♫
♫Our life is very fulfilling♫
♫我们的生活很充实♫
♫ With joy and sadness ♫
♫ 带着喜悦和悲伤 ♫
♫ Desire for crystallization♫
♫ 渴望结晶 ♫
♫ Enter the bright galaxy ♫
♫ 进入明亮的星系 ♫
♫You turned around quietly♫
♫你静静地转过身♫
♫ Closed the marriage contract ♫
♫ 合上了婚书♫
If you don't fall to death, let her go.
如果你没有摔死的话就放她走吧。
Let go, let go.
放手，放手。
What are you doing? why is it you again?
你在干什么？怎么又是你？
leave.
离开。
forget it. let's go.
忘了它。我们走吧。
let's go.
我们走吧。
Why did you jump from there?
你为什么从那里跳下来？
I told you not to jump.
我告诉过你不要跳。
Why don't you listen?
你为什么不听？
Do you know how dangerous this is?
你知道这有多危险吗？
Why do you say so much to him?
你为什么要对他说这么多？
Does he still look like he understands?
他看上去还像是听懂了的样子吗？
I see.
我明白。
So why do you do this?
那你为什么这么做呢？
you are always like this.
你总是这样。
When will people be able to worry less?
什么时候才能让人们少一些忧虑呢？
But I miss you very much.
但我非常想念你。
I don’t want to stay at the top.
我不想留在顶端。
Her brother is still alive.
她的兄弟还活着。
What did you say? rogue.
你说什么？流氓。
Let her go.
放开她。
- No, I will not. - let go.
- 不，我不会。 - 松手。
I won't.
我不会。
I will hit you.
我会打你。
He San, I dare you.
何三，我敢你。
Go get the horse.
去牵马吧。
go.
去。
You can't jump from a high place.
你不能从高处跳下来。
do you understand?
你明白吗？
Why are you here alone?
你怎么一个人在这里？
Where are Heshan and Zhanping?
Where are Heshan and Zhanping?
I have no idea.
我不知道。
So what are you doing here?
那你来这里做什么？
I'm here to find you.
我是来找你的。
Come to me?
来找我？
Because I saw you in the night sky.
因为我在夜空中看到了你。
Is she your sister?
她是你妹妹吗？
I have no idea
我不知道
If she were my sister.
如果她是我妹妹的话。
let's go.
我们走吧。
If you can't eat shrimp, don't eat it.
如果不能吃虾，就不要吃。
This would be a waste.
这将是一种浪费。
So, this is He Jiuling’s
所以，这是何九龄的
The legendary husband, right?
传说中的老公吧？
Not really.
并不真地。
why not?
为什么不？
No matter what, my father and we would never agree.
无论如何，父亲和我们永远不会同意。
Besides, we have already fallen out with the Rong family.
再说了，我们已经 和荣家闹翻了。
If only he could be with your annoying sister
如果他能和你烦人的妹妹在一起就好了
That would be nice.
那样就好了。
Second sister-in-law, I used to think you didn’t have much taste.
二嫂， 我以前觉得你没多大品味
When you pursue my second brother.
当你追求我二哥的时候。
I'm more sure now.
我现在更加确定了。
When he became famous,
当他出名的时候，
I don’t think he’s worthy of Jiuling.
我觉得他配不上九灵。
But you think it's okay for him to be like this.
但你觉得他这样就好了。
look.
看。
He only had He Jiuling in his eyes.
他的眼里只有贺九菱。
He Jiuling is so annoying.
何九龄实在是太烦人了。
I'm going to buy some herbs to apply on red dates.
我准备去买一些草药 来敷红枣。
You guys eat
你们吃饭吧
go ahead.
前进。
Peel your own shrimp.
自己剥虾。
[Kaiyuan Inn]
[Kaiyuan Inn]
- We're renting four empty rooms. - Okay, ma'am.
- 我们要租四间空房间。 - 好吧，小姐。
There are exactly four empty rooms on the second floor.
二楼正好有四个空房间。
You depend on my sister for food and life.
你靠我妹妹吃饭和生活。
As an adult, you still have to have some dignity.
作为一个成年人，还是要有一点尊严的。
- Thanks. -How can you be so shameless?
- 谢谢。 -你怎么可以这么无耻
Still spending a woman’s money?
还花女人的钱？
What is less?
什么是少？
Boss, can you help me carry my luggage upstairs?
老板，你能帮我 把行李搬上楼吗？
not lower than. shameless.
不低于。不要脸。
It means happiness.
就是快乐的意思。
I asked you how you can be so happy
我问你怎么可以这么开心
Spend your sister's money.
花姐姐的钱。
I am very happy.
我很高兴。
No, I get a headache every time I talk to you.
不，每次和你说话我就头疼。
He San, please take Rong Yu upstairs first.
禾三，你先带容羽上楼吧。
I'll see how I can contact Heshan.
我看看怎样才能联系到鹤山。
He and Zhanping must be worried.
他和展平肯定很担心。
Why are you following me?
你为什么跟着我？
I can't work with you.
我不能和你一起工作。
Let's go upstairs and rest first.
先上楼休息吧。
I will go with you.
我和你一起去。
I'll be back in a moment.
我一会儿就回来。
I'm scared.
我很害怕。
Master Rong,
容少爷，
Let me tell you about He Jiuling
让我告诉你何九龄的
stories in Nanjiang.
stories in Nanjiang.
Look, this cloak you're wearing
你看，你穿的这件斗篷
It’s the wolf from He Jiuling
是来自何九龄的狼
Hunting takes a lot of risk.
冒着很大的风险去狩猎。
It's cold and snowy...
天气又冷又下雪……
stop. You won't find her.
停止。你将找不到她。
That time, the wolf almost killed He Jiuling.
那一次，那头狼差点杀了贺九菱。
if she died,
如果她死了，
You will never see her again.
你再也见不到她了。
You can't find her anywhere.
你到处都找不到她。
Will I never see her again?
再也见不到她了吗？
can't find her
找不到她
Anywhere?
任何地方？
Second sister-in-law, look what you did to him.
二嫂， 你看看你对他做了什么。
I did nothing.
我什么也没做。
You can't blame me.
你不能怪我。
Besides, he is not here to find He Jiuling now.
再说了，他现在也不是来找贺九菱的。
It is not good?
这不是很好吗？
you…
你…
Master Rong.
容少爷。
It's been so long.
已经过去这么久了。
Why are you still upset?
为什么你还心烦意乱？
Oh my god, don't do this, okay?
天哪，不要这样，好吗？
As men, we should not cry,
作为男人，我们不应该哭泣，
Even if we die.
即使我们死了。
Also, let me tell you,
另外，我告诉你，
He Jiuling hated men crying the most.
贺九龄最讨厌男人哭。
You are so cowardly
你真是太懦弱了
She will hate you forever.
她会恨你一辈子。
Did you hear me? Turn it off.
你听到我说话了吗？把它关掉。
He Qiuting, did you do well?
何秋婷，干得好吧？
Why are you poking me?
你为什么戳我？
Why did you hit Rong Yu?
你为什么打容羽？
Do you think he is easily bullied?
你觉得他容易欺负吗？
I didn't hit him.
我没有打他。
Can you try to understand the situation first?
你能先试着了解一下情况吗？
I didn't bully him.
我没有欺负他。
Second sister-in-law, please help me.
二嫂，帮帮我吧。
say something.
说些什么。
I'm tired. Go to bed now.
我累了。现在去睡觉了。
Yang Ying.
Yang Ying.
Do you want to provoke confrontation between us?
你是想挑拨我们的对立吗？
It doesn't matter. Do not be afraid.
没关系。别害怕。
you. Stop pretending.
你。别再假装了。
I did nothing.
我什么也没做。
Why are you acting so hurt?
你为什么表现得这么受伤？
Let her go.
放开她。
Take your hands off her.
把你的手从她身上拿开。
Don't touch him.
别碰他。
You didn't like him at first glance.
你第一眼看上去并不喜欢他。
You always laugh at him.
你总是嘲笑他。
- I... - I pretended not to hear,
- 我…… - 我假装没听见，
But that doesn't mean I can accept it.
但这并不意味着我可以接受。
I will never leave you to anyone else again.
以后我不会把你留给别人了。
No matter where I go I will take you with me
无论我去哪里我都会带着你
Until Heshan arrived.
直到鹤山到来。
My fault. sorry.
我的错。对不起。
He Jiuling, are you crazy?
何九菱，你疯了吗？
You run around taking care of him.
你跑来跑去照顾他
Going out late at night to find someone to pick him up,
深夜出去找人接他，
Now you are apologizing to him.
现在你还向他道歉。
sleep.
睡觉。
Go to bed now.
现在去睡觉。
It was unbearable.
实在难以忍受。
I have been away from the capital for four years,
我离开首都四年了，
The idiots out there have become powerful.
那里的白痴已经变得强大了。
You can spend the night here.
你可以在这里过夜。
My room is next door.
我的房间就在隔壁。
If you need anything, just push the door open and come in.
如果您需要什么， 只需推门进来即可。
sleep tight.
睡个好觉。
What?
什么？
sleep.
睡觉。
This is your room.
这是你的房间。
Go in and sleep.
进去就可以睡觉了。
I sleep with you.
我和你一起睡。
No, this is inappropriate.
不，这是不合适的。
We used to sleep together.
我们以前经常一起睡。
This is not true. Stop talking nonsense.
这不是真的。别废话了。
We did it. You took off my shoes.
我们做到了。你脱掉了我的鞋子。
We also share a quilt.
我们还共用一床被子。
me……
我，我……
We share a quilt.
我们共用一床被子。
I hugged you.
我拥抱了你。
All right.
好吧。
That time we shared a room
那次我们住一间房
Because we have to.
因为我们不得不这样做。
But now, we have two rooms.
但现在，我们有两个房间。
In addition, men and women
除此之外，男人女人
before they got married,
在他们结婚之前，
Can't sleep together.
不能睡在一起。
You understand this, right?
你明白这一点，对吧？
beautiful.
美好的。
Did I make things too complicated?
是我把事情搞得太复杂了吗？
You have to listen to me from now on
以后你要听我的话
knew?
知道了？
Okay, I'll make your bed.
好吧，我去给你整理床铺。
Your bed is ready.
你的床已经准备好了。
You should go to bed now. I am leaving.
你现在应该去睡觉了。我走了。
Why are you following me again?
你怎么又跟着我了？
sleep.
睡觉。
Didn’t we just agree?
我们刚才不是已经同意了吗？
You will listen to me.
你会听我说的。
I will listen to you.
我会听你的。
You said you would take me with you
你说你会带我一起走
Until the flattening comes.
直到展平来了。
I...I listen to you.
我……我听你的。
This is not what I just said...
这不是我刚才说的……
hurry up.
快点。
You lied to me, didn't you?
你骗了我，不是吗？
So many people lied to me.
这么多人对我撒了谎。
They said you left,
他们说你离开了，
you do not want to see me
你不想见我
And you'll never come back.
而你永远不会回来。
They also said they had seen you
他们还说见过你
But those who took me to you
但那些带我去找你的人
After a while it disappeared.
过了一会儿就消失了。
They all lied to me and you lied to me.
他们都骗了我，你也骗了我。
No, I didn't lie to you.
不，我没有骗你。
you did it.
你做到了。
I really didn't lie to you.
我真的没有骗你。
It's just...I just...
只是……我只是……
I went to the next room to get the quilt.
我去隔壁房间拿被子。
I…
我…
I really didn't lie to you.
真的没有骗你。
Really?
真的吗？
Sister-in-law, do you know?
嫂子你知道吗
What kind of person am I, right?
我是一个什么样的人，对吗？
Don't tell when we arrive in the capital
当我们到达首都时，不要告诉
Is there anyone else who is my second brother?
我二哥还有其他人好吗？
You had trouble with him before,
之前你和他有过纠缠，
Now you want to fuck again
现在你又想乱搞
No responsibility, right?
不承担责任，对吗？
Don't worry, sister-in-law.
别担心，嫂子。
Master Rong is stupid, so I can pretend to be stupid.
容少爷傻， 我也可以装傻。
no no.
不，不。
It's cold. Keep yourself warm.
是冷的。让自己保持温暖。
Sister-in-law, come back and clarify what you mean.
嫂子，你回来 澄清一下你的意思。
We will be warm.
我们会很温暖。
I'll keep you warm.
我会让你温暖。
Okay, okay. Good night.
可以了，好了。晚安。
not yet.
还没有。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
Aren't you going to sleep?
你不去睡觉吗？
I'm worried you'll leave.
我担心你会离开。
I will not leave.
我不会离开。
Won't you leave in the future?
以后你不会离开吗？
I miss you. Do you miss me?
我想你。你想念我吗？
Can I sleep with you?
我可以和你一起睡吗？
Rong Yu, go back to bed.
容宇，你回床上去吧。
I...I didn't hear clearly just now.
我……我刚才没听清楚。
I answered wrongly.
我回答错了。
You lied to me again.
你又骗我了。
Why did I lie to you again?
我怎么又骗你了？
You just agreed.
你刚才就同意了。
I...I didn't realize it.
我……我没有意识到。
forget it.
忘了它。
It's okay with you.
你没关系。
You don't understand anything now.
你现在什么都不明白。
Rong Yu.
Rong Yu.
Believe me.
相信我。
He Jiuling will definitely cure you.
贺九龄一定能治好你。
But you have to wait for a while.
但你必须等待一段时间。
I've been looking for you for a long time.
我找你很久了。
sorry.
对不起。
It doesn't matter.
没关系。
Why are you so good?
你为什么这么好？
if you could be a little selfish
如果你可以自私一点
Or even more annoying,
或者更烦人的，
I probably wouldn't be so sad anymore.
我大概就不会这么难过了。
As the days pass,
随着日子一天天过去，
The longer I know you, the more I owe you.
我认识你的时间越长，我欠你的就越多。
When can I repay you?
我什么时候才能报答你呢？
You're sleepy, right?
你困了，对吧？
Come on, let's go to bed. It's cold on the ground.
来吧，我们去睡觉吧。 地上很冷。
IM thirsty.
我口渴。
I'll get you a cup of tea.
我去给你倒杯茶。
The tea doesn't taste very good.
茶的味道不太好。
Then I'll go get it...
那我就去拿……
Rong Yu. Rong Yu.
Rong Yu. Rong Yu.
【Wu's Steamed Bun Shop】
【吴氏包子店】
Please give me a pot of hot water.
请给我一壶热水。
OK
好的。
Master Qiuting.
Master Qiuting.
You are so fast. Come.
你真快。来。
Fortunately this is a suburb of the capital.
幸好这里是首都郊区。
I came as quickly as I could.
我尽快赶来了。
Jiuling, are you there?
九龄，你在吗？
Jiuling.
Jiuling.
Who is this?
这是谁？
He is from Rong Mansion, here to pick up Rong Yu.
他是容府来的， 是来接容羽的。
Jiuling, I'm coming in.
九龄，我进来了。
He Jiuling sent a message last night,
昨晚何九菱发消息，
He came in the morning.
他早上就来了。
That's quick.
那很快。
Hold on.
稍等。
what for?
做什么的？
We should get rid of this hot potato as soon as possible.
我们应该尽快摆脱这个烫手山芋。
Master Rong, Master Rong.
荣师傅，荣师傅。
Someone is coming to pick you up.
有人来接你了。
Master Qiuting, is my master here?
秋亭大师，我师父在吗？
You must never let your master come out and cause trouble again.
绝对不能再让你的主人出来 惹麻烦了。
Either die in 15 minutes
15分钟后要么死
Or get lost.
或迷路。
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling, come out!
贺九菱，你出来吧！
He Jiuling, come out quickly!
贺九菱，你赶紧出来！
Why are you yelling?
你为什么大喊大叫？
He Jiuling, come out. come out.
何九龄，你出来吧。出来。
——He Jiuling. - Why are you yelling so early in the morning?
——何九龄。 - 你为什么大清早的大喊大叫？
I want to ask you what you are doing.
我想问你在做什么。
I'm very angry now.
我现在很生气。
Don't anger me. Come out now.
别激怒我。现在就出来吧。
He Jiuling, if you don’t come out, I will go in.
何九菱，你再不出来， 我就进去了。
- Stop knocking. - come out.
- 别敲了。 - 出来。
Did you hear me?
你听到我说话了吗？
open the door.
打开门。
Master.
少爷。
- Heshan. - Rong Yu.
- Heshan. - Rong Yu.
I will tear you apart.
我会把你撕碎。
♫ Under the sunset♫
♫ 黄昏夕阳下♫
♫I have traveled thousands of miles♫
♫我行万里路♫
♫Playing the piano under the moonlight♫
♫月光下弹琴♫
♫ Drinks won’t let me forget ♫
♫ 饮料不会让我忘记 ♫
♫Write down what I miss you♫
♫写下对你的思念♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫There is no escape from fate♫
♫命运无路可逃♫
♫Looking back, I see you waiting♫
♫回首，我看到你在等待♫
♫Our life is full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Longing to crystallize into a bright galaxy♫
♫ 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河♫
♫You turned around quietly and closed the marriage contract♫
♫你悄悄转身 ，合上婚书♫
♫Ask how many stars there are in the sky♫
♫问天上有多少颗星星♫
♫Write down what I miss you♫
♫写下对你的思念♫
♫Our destiny is written on paper♫
♫我们的命运写在纸上♫
♫ Like the strongest wine ♫
♫ 就像最烈的酒♫
♫There is no escape from fate♫
♫命运无路可逃♫
♫Looking back, I see you waiting♫
♫回首，我看到你在等待♫
♫Our life is full of joy and sadness♫
♫我们的生活充满欢乐和悲伤♫
♫ Longing to crystallize into a bright galaxy♫
♫ 渴望结晶 成明亮的银河♫
♫I play the piano gently, waiting for passers-by like you♫
♫我轻轻抚琴， 等待着你这样的路人♫
♫It turns out that you are my inseparable destiny♫
♫原来你是我不可分割的宿命♫